John A. Holmes Papers MS007
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Poetry, 1922 -- 1962; 1940 -- 1961; MS007.001; 7.25 Linear Feet; 1 Audiovisual Object(s)
  - Ladies and gentlemen ..., MS007.001.009.00859; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 032.
  - Last night, MS007.001.009.00860; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 033. Annotated.
  - Letter to a young poet, MS007.001.009.00861; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 034. Revision in 9:035 titled: A little night-wording. Revision in 9:035 is annotated. revisions in 9:035 and 10:037, p. 85
  - Letters: a metaphor, 1962-04-22; MS007.001.009.00862; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 038.
  - A long poem entitled "I love the Hillside Hardware & Paint Co.", 1953-03-28; MS007.001.009.00863; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 041. revision in 10:035, p. 60
  - First love recalled, MS007.001.009.00864; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 044. Handwritten
  - A man who came home late at night, MS007.001.009.00865; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 045. revisions in 10:010, p. 102 and 10:035, p. 154
  - Margaret, MS007.001.009.00866; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 047. Duplicate in 10:036, p. 85: "I wrote this household verse while Margaret and Doris were still in the hospital, and put a large copy in the nursery, for homecoming." duplicate in 10:036, p. 85
  - Music to me, 1954-03-16; MS007.001.009.00867; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 051.
  - My pasenger [My passenger], MS007.001.009.00868; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 052.
  - My wife's grandfather's ring, 1955-09-01; MS007.001.009.00869; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 053. duplicate in 10:035, p. 12 and revision in 10:037, p. 17
  - New name, MS007.001.009.00870; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 055. duplicate in 10:035, p. 65
  - New woman in the house, MS007.001.009.00871; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 058. revisions in 10:036, p. 94 and 10:037, p. 26, duplicate in 10:037, p. 80
  - Next year's music, 1948-02-16; MS007.001.009.00872; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 059. revisions in 9:060 and 9:061
  - No more music, 1954-03-14; MS007.001.009.00873; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 062.
  - One act play, MS007.001.009.00874; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 067.
  - One beautiful moment, MS007.001.009.00875; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 069.
  - Love-child, MS007.001.009.00876; Holmes, John (Box 9)
  - The cottage of broken dreams, MS007.001.009.00877; Holmes, John (Box 9)
  - Woodrow-Wilson was-a-hero, MS007.001.009.00878; Holmes, John (Box 9)
  - Open letter [Maybe you], MS007.001.009.00879; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 072. Slightly different version entitled "Maybe You", added Jaune 2009. revisions in 10:037, p. 32 and 10:037, p. 79
  - Preface, 1949-12-24; MS007.001.009.00880; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 075. Published in The Gothic Look (s l: Privately printed, 1957) p. ix-xii.
  - Winter solstice, 1949-12-24; MS007.001.009.00881; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 075. Published in The double root, p. 59; YWCA Magazine, 51:29, December 1957; New York Times Book Review, July 22 1962, p. 2. Printed on Christmas card for 1956. sound recording in 64:001
  - Look east, look west, 1949-12-24; MS007.001.009.00882; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 075. revision in 10:037, p. 95
  - The weight, 1949-12-24; MS007.001.009.00883; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 075.
  - Past understanding, 1949-12-24; MS007.001.009.00884; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 075. Published in Beloit Poetry Journal, 1:14, Fall 1950. duplicate in 10:035, p. 107
  - A station in the journey, 1949-12-24; MS007.001.009.00885; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 075. Published in The double root, p. 18.
  - Interruption, 1949-12-24; MS007.001.009.00886; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 075. Published in The double root, p. 68; Saturday Review of Literature, 33:33, July 22, 1950. sound recording in 64:001
  - 1918: Armistice, 1949-12-24; MS007.001.009.00887; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 075. Published in The double root, p. 16.
  - The change, 1949-12-24; MS007.001.009.00888; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 075. Published in Beloit Poetry Journal, 1:12, Fall 1950.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.009.00889; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 077. revision in 9:078
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.009.00890; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 079.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.009.00891; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 082.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.009.00892; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 089.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.009.00893; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 091.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.009.00894; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 092.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.009.00895; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 097.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.009.00896; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 106.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.009.00897; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 114.
  - Historical event, MS007.001.010.00898; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 003.
  - All the dead and some poets, MS007.001.010.00899; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 004. Notes by Anna Beatrice Murphy revision in 10:035, p. 171
  - The world in my time [The world in my own time], MS007.001.010.00900; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010. Collected in poetry binder, p. 17 revision in 10:034, p. 16 and duplicate in 10:035, p. 127
  - Whose name was writ in water, 1935; MS007.001.010.00901; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 011. Published in Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1935, (New York, Poetry Digest Association, 1936), p. 73; Too Many Bears, and Other Stories (Boston: Ginn, 1936) p. 733; Poetry Digest, 1:7, March 1935; Voices, 80:4, February-March 1935. revisions in 10:010, p. 81 and 10:035, p. 144
  - Warning, 1935; MS007.001.010.00902; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 011. Published in Fiction Parade, 1:281, July 1935; Voices, 80:5, February-March 1935. duplicate in 10:010, p. 82
  - Primitive, 1935; MS007.001.010.00903; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 011. Revision in 10:010 is annotated. Published in Voices, 80:7, Februrary-March 1935. revision in 10:010, p. 83 and duplicate in 10:035, p. 146
  - Totem, 1960; MS007.001.010.00904; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 012. Published in The fortune teller, p. 60; Audience, 7:93, Spring 1960. duplicate in 10:037, p. 130 and revision in 11:003, p. 50
  - Slow child, 1943; MS007.001.010.00905; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 013. Published in Fair warning, p. 7; Better Health, 16:3, December-February 1943-4.
  - This time surely, 1935; MS007.001.010.00906; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 015. Duplicate in 10:010 is annotated. Published in Address to the living, p. 44; American Mercury, 36:168, October 1935; American Mercury Digest, p. 31, Spring 1936; Fiction Parade and Golden Book Magazine, 5:44, May 1937. revisions in 10:017 and 10:038, p. 15, duplicate in 10:010, p. 79
  - Portrait: My wife, 1960; MS007.001.010.00907; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 016. Published in The fortune teller, p. 64; Poetry Northwest, 1:6, Spring-Summer 1960. revisions in 10:037, p. 142 and 11:003, p. 54, sound recording in 66:001
  - The island, MS007.001.010.00908; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 019. Published in Map of my country, p. 85; American Prefaces, 6:233, Spring 1941. duplicate in 11:002, p. 81
  - You have an interesting mind, MS007.001.010.00909; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 021. Revision in 10:036, p. 24 is annotated. Published in Patterns, 1:43, January 1955. revisions in 10:036, p. 24 and 10:037, p. 11
  - The world is one, MS007.001.010.00910; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 022. Published in Address to the living, p. 53; Tuftonian n s, 9:135-40, June 1935. revision in 10:010, p.69
  - A man's world, MS007.001.010.00911; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 023. Revision in 10:010 is annotated. Published in Voices, 87:6, Autumn 1936. revision in 10:010, p. 115
  - Child: Spring, 1950; MS007.001.010.00912; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 024. Published in Hopkins Review, 3:26, Winter 1950. duplicate in 10:035, p. 18
  - Cook's tour, MS007.001.010.00913; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 025. Published in Fair warning, p. 99; American Cookery, 47:173, November 1941; New Yorker, 11:22, September 14, 1935. duplicate in 10:010, p.106 and revision in 10:038, p. 23
  - A room with books [Room with books], 1956; MS007.001.010.00914; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 026. Published in Lyric, 36:76, Fall 1956. duplicate in 10:037, p. 71
  - Far enough, 1955; MS007.001.010.00915; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 028. Published in Fine Arts Magazine, 5:33, April 1960; Patterns, 1:53, January 1955. revision in 10:036, p. 28 and duplicate in 10:037, p. 12
  - Hat weather, 1953; MS007.001.010.00916; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 029. Revision in 10:035, p. 97 is annotated. Published in University of Kansas City Review, 20:56, Autumn 1953; Yankee, 20:39, May 1956. revision in 10:035, p. 97 and duplicate in 10:037, p. 9
  - The late Mr. Thorpe, 1935; MS007.001.010.00917; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 030. Published in Atlantic, 156:756, December 1935; Briefs from the Atlantic Monthly, p. 77, 1936.
  - Looking at books, 1939; MS007.001.010.00918; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 031. Published in Horn Book, 15:357, November-December 1939.
  - A natural law, 1959; MS007.001.010.00919; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 032. Published in Lyric, 39:9, Winter 1959. duplicate in 10:037, p. 119
  - First day, 1944; MS007.001.010.00920; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 033, p. 19. Published in Along the row, p. 16; Chistian Register, 123:57, February 1944. revisions in 10:035, p. 163; 10:035, p. 175; 11:002, p. 101
  - Being young, 1935; MS007.001.010.00921; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 78. Published in Address to the living, p. 77; Atlantic, 156:62-63, July 1935. revision in 10:038, p. 20
  - Fable with no moral, 1935; MS007.001.010.00922; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 86. Published in Fair warning, p. 85; Address to the living, p. 85; The New Yorker Book of Verse (New York: Harcourt, Brace, 1935) p. 48-49.
  - Mornings at eleven, MS007.001.010.00923; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 87. Published in Fair warning, p. 83; Address to the living, p. 83.
  - The bookworm turns, 1935; MS007.001.010.00924; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 88. Published in Fair warning, p. 79; New Yorker, 11:32, March 16, 1935; Norfolk Virginian Pilot, August 12 1935.
  - A sweet hope once, MS007.001.010.00925; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 89. Published in Address to the living, p. 97.
  - Sweetly solemn thought, 1935; MS007.001.010.00926; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 104. Published in Fair warning, p. 47; New Yorker, 11:16, August 31, 1935.
  - Those were the days, 1935; MS007.001.010.00927; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 105. Published in Fair warning, p. 87; New Yorker, 11:50, July 20, 1935.
  - Table for one, 1935; MS007.001.010.00928; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 111. Published in Fair warning, p. 50; New Yorker, 11:36, October 19, 1935.
  - Work in progress, 1936; MS007.001.010.00929; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 113. Published in Fair warning, p. 77; New Yorker, 12:20, May 23, 1936.
  - The critic on the pan, 1936; MS007.001.010.00930; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 114. Published in Fair warning, p. 75; Kansas City Independent, September 12 1936; Kansas City Times, September 21 1936; New York Times Book Review, September 20 1936; Quincy, Massachusetts Patriot Ledger, September 30 1938.
  - Dinner for eight, MS007.001.010.00931; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 115. Annotated.
  - The miserable gardener, 1936; MS007.001.010.00932; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 116. Published in Fair warning, p. 11; New Yorker, 12:60, April 25, 1936.
  - Good-night! Good-night!, MS007.001.010.00933; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 117.
  - Letter to three men, MS007.001.010.00934; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 118. Published in Map of my country, p. 53 revision in 11:002, p. 52
  - Political strategy, 1936; MS007.001.010.00935; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 125. Published in Fair warning, p. 17; New Yorker, 12:29, October 10, 1936.
  - To my teachers, 1958; MS007.001.010.00936; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 126. Published in Address to the living, p. 99; Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1958 (New York: Schulte, 1959) p. 103. Printed on Christmas card for 1957.
  - Notes for a history of sleep, 1938; MS007.001.010.00937; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 137. Published in Fair warning, p. 42; New Yorker, 14:20, July 2, 1938. revision in 10:035, p. 160
  - Thinker in bed, 1938; MS007.001.010.00938; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 139. Published in Fair warning, p. 65; New Yorker, 13:32, January 15, 1938.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.010.00939; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 034, p. 83. Accompanied with sketch.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.010.00940; Holmes, John (Box 10)
  - Design for a skyscraper, MS007.001.010.00941; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 034, p. 87.
  - Problem father, 1937; MS007.001.010.00942; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 143. Published in Fair warning, p. 5; Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1937, ( New York: Paebar, 1938), p. 76; New Yorker, 12:59, September 25 1937; Lewiston, Maine Journal, October 22 1937.
  - Wallpaper poem, MS007.001.010.00943; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 144.
  - The double life, 1938; MS007.001.010.00944; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 145. Published in New Yorker, 14:58, October 29, 1938.
  - Fair warning, 1938; MS007.001.010.00945; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 146. Published in Fair warning, p. 3; New Yorker, 14:30, October 1, 1938; Tuftonian 8, no. 2:8, 1950.
  - This one is father, 1938; MS007.001.010.00946; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 010, p. 150. Published in Fair warning, p. 61; New Yorker, 14:33, December 3, 1938.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.010.00947; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 034, p. 97. Handwritten
  - Incredulous, MS007.001.010.00948; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 034, p. 100. Handwritten
  - A year after, MS007.001.010.00949; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 034, p. 103. Handwritten
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.010.00950; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 034, p. 104. Handwritten
  - Ode for the hundredth birthday of William Upham, MS007.001.010.00951; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 034, p. 105.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.010.00952; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 034, p. 107.
  - Peter sleeping, MS007.001.010.00953; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 034, p. 111.
  - Epitaph for any New Yorker, MS007.001.010.00954; Holmes, John (Box 10)
  - Peter reads far into the night, MS007.001.010.00955; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 034, p. 124. Handwritten
  - Letter from an exile, 1929; MS007.001.010.00956; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 034, p. 143. Annotated Published in Boston Herald, March 9 1929.
  - Usually, MS007.001.010.00957; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 035, p. 57. Published in The symbols, p. 41.
  - The blessing, 1953; MS007.001.010.00958; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 035, p. 102. Published in University of Kansas City Review, 19:233, June 1953.
  - Nineteen fifty one, MS007.001.010.00959; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 035, p. 108.
  - Old cheese and cold beer, MS007.001.010.00960; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 035, p. 165. Published in The double root, p. 30.
  - What the book salesman said, MS007.001.010.00961; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 035, p. 168.
  - Words enough, 1955; MS007.001.010.00962; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 035, p. 169. Published in New York Herald-Tribune, October 13 1955.
  - Do you remember, MS007.001.010.00963; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 035, p. 172. Annotated
  - The hunted, 1942; MS007.001.010.00964; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 035, p. 174. Published in Tuftonian, 3:18, November 1942.
  - Tomorrow you, 1942; MS007.001.010.00965; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 035, p. 174. Published in Map of my country, p. 64; Along the row, p. 29; A Treasury of Favorite Poems (New York: Hawthorn, 1963) p. 84; This Is My America: Poems from the Washington Post (Washington, D.C.: Washington Post, 1946) p. 94; Tuftonian, 3:17, November 1942.
  - Ballad of some of the boys, 1943; MS007.001.010.00966; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 035, p. 176. Published in Along the row, p. 35; Tuftonian, 3:96, January 1943.
  - The talking mirror, MS007.001.010.00967; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 035, p. 178.
  - Color, MS007.001.010.00968; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 035, p. 182.
  - The day's news, MS007.001.010.00969; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 035, p. 183.
  - What we hate most, MS007.001.010.00970; Holmes, John (Box 10)
  - The snow-child, MS007.001.010.00971; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 035, p. 184.
  - For Karl Magnus Armens, MS007.001.010.00972; Holmes, John (Box 10)
  - Boy at four, 1954; MS007.001.010.00973; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 036, p. 5. Annotated: Long note on back about Holmes' son's reaction to the poem. Published in New York Herald-Tribune, June 12 1954. duplicate in 10:037, p. 1
  - Hummingbird and seagull, 1955; MS007.001.010.00974; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 036, p. 27. Annotated. Published in The fortune teller, p. 32; New World Writing: Eighth Mentor Selection (New York: New American Library, 1955) p. 160. Revision in 11:005 is annotated: "--for Rebecca remembering May 24th 1955" duplicate in 10:037, p. 8 and 11:003, p. 30; revision in 11:005, sound recording in 65:001
  - The extent of his acres, 1954; MS007.001.010.00975; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 34. Published in Tuftonian, 10:28-29, April 1954.
  - To remember one another, 1954; MS007.001.010.00976; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 37. Published in 1929 Tufts-Jackson 25th Reunion Book (s l: n p, 1954) p. 9-10.
  - All's well that ends, 1956; MS007.001.010.00977; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 59. Published in Beloit Poetry Journal, 7:33-34, Winter 1956-7.
  - John Holmes, his book, 1956; MS007.001.010.00978; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 71. Published in New York Herald-Tribune, June 22 1956.
  - The chance, 1957; MS007.001.010.00979; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 84. Published in The fortune teller, p. 65; New Poems by American Poets: No. 2 Edited by Rolfe Humphries (New York: Ballantine, 1957) p. 74; Nation, 184:143, February 16, 1957. duplicate in 11:003, p. 55
  - Lesson in the monkey-house, 1957; MS007.001.010.00980; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 88. Published in The fortune teller, p. 9; Literary Review, 1:220, Winter 1957-58. revision in 11:003, p. 7
  - The title-page, 1957; MS007.001.010.00981; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 96. Collection of "Seven poems, 1957 Tufts Jumbo Book"
  - Faculty and administration section, 1957; MS007.001.010.00982; Holmes, John (Box 10)
  - The senior class section, 1957; MS007.001.010.00983; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 97. Collection of "Seven poems, 1957 Tufts Jumbo Book"
  - The activities section, 1957; MS007.001.010.00984; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 98. Collection of "Seven poems, 1957 Tufts Jumbo Book"
  - The organizations section, 1957; MS007.001.010.00985; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 99. Collection of "Seven poems, 1957 Tufts Jumbo Book"
  - The fraternities section, 1957; MS007.001.010.00986; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 100. Collection of "Seven poems, 1957 Tufts Jumbo Book"
  - Ode for scene 1, "Hullaballou", MS007.001.010.00987; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 104.
  - Poetry defined, 1958; MS007.001.010.00988; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 114. Published in The fortune teller, p. 29; Best Poems of 1958 (Palo Alto, CA: Pacific Books, 1960) p. 43; Saturday Review, 41:20, March 1, 1958. duplicate in 11:003, p. 27
  - On a cage of mice brought home for the week of school vacation, 1959; MS007.001.010.00989; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 120. Published in The fortune teller, p. 55; Harper, 218:57, May 1959. duplicate in 11:003, p. 48 and sound recording in 66:001
  - Nothing odd, MS007.001.010.00990; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 126. Published in The fortune teller, p. 70 duplicate in 11:003, p. 59
  - Free will and fire-truck, 1959; MS007.001.010.00991; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 129. Published in The fortune teller, p. 5; Massachusetts Review, 1:61, Fall 1959. duplicate in 11:003, p. 3
  - Verses in a very old tradition, MS007.001.010.00992; Holmes, John (Box 10)
    Box 10 folder 037, p. 174. Published in Hudson Review, 15:533, Winter 1962/63.
  - The stone, 1940; MS007.001.011.00993; Holmes, John (Box 11)
    Box 11 folder 002, p. 45. Published in Map of my country, p. 43; Lyric, 19:52, Winter 1940. Printed on Christmas card for 1955.
  - The spring sun, MS007.001.011.00994; Holmes, John (Box 11)
    Box 11 folder 002, p. 62. Annotated. Published in Map of my country, p. 63; Along the row, p. 28.
  - The fifty-first, MS007.001.011.00995; Holmes, John (Box 11)
    Box 11 folder 002, p. 64. Annotated: Poem is crossed out, with note that poem is "not in the book" (folder contains typescript draft of manuscript for Map of My Country).
  - Overheard, MS007.001.011.00996; Holmes, John (Box 11)
    Box 11 folder 002, p. 86. Published in Map of my country, p. 89
  - A prayer, MS007.001.011.00997; Holmes, John (Box 11)
    Box 11 folder 002, p. 90. Published in Map of my country, p. 93
  - Evening meal in the twentieth century, 1939; MS007.001.011.00998; Holmes, John (Box 11)
    Box 11 folder 002, p. 95. Published in Map of my country, p. 98; Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1938-1942 and Yearbook of American Poetry, (New York: Paebar, 1942), p. 221; Mid-Century American Poets (New York: Twayne, 1950) p. 219; Atlantic, 164:634, November 1939; Tuftonian n s, 14:95, Spring 1940. sound recording in 64:001
  - A little night-wording, MS007.001.011.00999; Holmes, John (Box 11)
    Box 11 folder 003, p. 12. Published in The fortune teller, p. 14
  - The Bollingen Poetry Readings, Wednesday, 1961-10-25; MS007.001.062.00001; Holmes, John (Box 62)
    Order of program: Holiday with gods; The fortune teller
  - The eleventh commandment, UNH, 1956-08-14; MS007.001.063.00001; Holmes, John (Box 63)
    Order of program: Eleventh commandment
  - John Holmes reading his poetry, reel 1 of 2, 1951-05-15; MS007.001.064.00001; Holmes, John (Box 64)
    Recorded on both sides. Order of program: Memorandum of agreement; Fear of dying; From Brooklyn; The spiral; The broken one; Winter Solstice; Interruption; Errata; Herself; Plain girl, Sunday noon; The water poem; Ten thirty class; Puritan ancestor; Essay on misery; Evening meal in the twentieth century; Prayer on the night before Easter; Weather making; Grass; Cow be killed; The overgrown back yard; Bucyrus; Carry me back; Birthday; All's well that ends; One day's rain; Out of the room; The letter; The oyster
  - John Holmes reading his poetry, reel 2 of 2, 1951-05-15; MS007.001.065.00001; Holmes, John (Box 65)
    Order of program: The oyster [fragment]; The eleventh commandment; Hummingbird and seagull